<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<executable>
  <category>;Segmentation.Bender</category>
  <index>3</index>
  <title>Compute Armature Weight</title>
  <description><![CDATA[Compute the weight of the <b>Input Armature</b> edges for each voxel of the <b>Input Rest Labelmap</b> using heat diffusion. <p>This module outputs a serie of files named "weight_i.mha" in the <b>Weight Output Directory</b>, where each voxel has the weight associated to the armature edge #i from the <b>Input Armature</b>.</p><p>When computing non-binary weight, the skeleton voxels of the <b>Input Rest Labelmap</b> (inside the partition given by the <b>Input Skinned Labelmap</b>) are used as hot source for the heat-diffusion process. This means that any bone within the weight partition will have a weight of 1. This implies that if that edge is posed, the bone will move completely with that edge. The other voxels weight is determined by diffusing the weight from the hot sources (i.e. bones).</p>]]>
  </description>
  <version>1.0.0</version>
  <documentation-url>http://public.kitware.com/Wiki/Bender/Documentation/1.0/Modules/ComputeArmatureWeight</documentation-url>
  <license/>
  <contributor>Yuanxin Liu (Kitware), Julien Finet (Kitware), Johan Andruejol (Kitware)</contributor>
  <acknowledgements><![CDATA[Air Force Research Laboratories]]></acknowledgements>
  <parameters>
    <label>IO</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Input/output parameters]]></description>

    <image type="label">
      <name>RestLabelmap</name>
      <label>Input Rest Labelmap</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Labelmap for which the weights will be computed. This should be the labelmap for which the <b>Input Armature</b> was created and the <b>Input Skinned Labelmap</b> computed.]]></description>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>0</index>
    </image>

    <geometry fileExtensions=".vtk">
      <name>ArmaturePoly</name>
      <label>Input Armature</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Armature in rest position. This should be the armature associated with the <b>Input Skinned Labelmap</b>.]]></description>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>1</index>
    </geometry>

    <image type="label">
      <name>SkinnedVolume</name>
      <label>Input Skinned Labelmap</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Volume skinning associated with the <b>Input Armature</b>. This volume represents which voxel of the <b>Input Rest Labelmap</b> is associated to which <b>Input Rest Armature</b>'s edge.<p>For a given edge i of the <b>Input Rest Armature</b>, the volume region associated with it will have the label i + 2. The label 0 is reserved for the outside of the <Input Rest Labelmap</b> body and the label 1 for invalid areas.</p>]]></description>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>2</index>
    </image>

    <directory>
      <name>WeightDirectory</name>
      <label>Weight Output Directory</label>
      <description><![CDATA[The directory used to store the weight files. <p>This directory needs write access and enough space.</p>]]></description>
      <channel>output</channel>
      <index>3</index>
      <default>./</default>
    </directory>

  </parameters>

  <parameters>
    <label>Labels</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Set the input necessary labels value here.]]></description>
    <double>
      <name>BackgroundValue</name>
      <label>Background Value</label>
      <description><![CDATA[The voxel value considered as background. All the other voxel values will be treated as foreground.]]></description>
      <longflag>--backgroundValue</longflag>
      <default>0.</default>
    </double>
    <integer>
      <name>BoneLabel</name>
      <label>Bone Label</label>
      <description><![CDATA[The bone label is used as the source of the weight heat-diffusion process.<p>This means that the structure in the <b>Input Rest Labelmap</b> with this label will act as a bone for the other pixels. Any pixel within this structure will be posed exactly as its associated armature's edge. The other voxels will move according to the computed weight obtained from the heat diffusion process.</p><p>In a human model, it is advised to set the <b>Bone Label</b> to the <b>Input Rest Labelmap</b> bone label in order to mimick the human anatomy as closely as possible when posing the <b>Input Rest Labelmap</b>.</p>]]></description>
      <longflag>--boneLabel</longflag>
      <default>1</default>
    </integer>
  </parameters>

  <parameters>
    <label>Controls</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Control how the module operates.]]></description>
    <integer>
      <name>FirstEdge</name>
      <label>Start Edge</label>
      <description><![CDATA[The first <b>Input Armature</b> egde to process. This specifies the start of the continuous range of bones for which the weights will be generated.]]></description>
      <longflag>--first</longflag>
      <default>0</default>
    </integer>

    <integer>
      <name>LastEdge</name>
      <description><![CDATA[The last <b>Input Armature</b> egde to process. This specifies the end of the continuous range of bones for which the weights will be generated. If -1 is specifed, all the bones starting from <b>Start Edge</b> will be processed.]]></description>
      <label>End edge</label>
      <longflag>--last</longflag>
      <default>-1</default>
    </integer>

    <integer>
      <name>SmoothingIteration</name>
      <longflag>--smooth</longflag>
      <label>Smoothing Iteration Number</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Number of iterations used for smoothing the weights locally. This is only necessary because we restrict the solving to a local region]]></description>
      <default>10</default>
    </integer>

    <double>
      <name>ScaleFactor</name>
      <longflag>--scaleFactor</longflag>
      <label>Computation Scale Factor</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Scale factor applied to the input images to speed up the processing. <p>When different from 1, the input images will be downsampled before any processing. Then the weights are computed on the downsampled images. After the computation, the weights are upsampled back to the original input image spacing. It is highly encouraged to use a sparser spacing than the input image to prevent very slow computation.</p>]]></description>
      <default>2</default>
    </double>

    <integer>
      <name>Padding</name>
      <longflag>--padding</longflag>
      <label>Padding</label>
      <description><![CDATA[How far (in voxel units) outside the body the weight region will be computed. If any padding is precised, the weight will be computed using a dilated version of the input images.]]></description>
      <default>1</default>
    </integer>

    <boolean>
      <name>UseEnvelopes</name>
      <label>Use Armature Envelopes</label>
      <longflag>--useEnvelopes</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[Use the envelope radius of each armature bone segment or not.]]></description>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>

  </parameters>
  <parameters advanced="true">
    <label>Advanced</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Advanced properties]]></description>

    <boolean>
      <name>Debug</name>
      <label>Debug Mode</label>
      <longflag>--debug</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[Print debug logs and dump intermediate images. The debug information will be outputed to a "Debug" folder in the <b>Weight Output Directory</b>.]]></description>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>

    <boolean>
      <name>IsArmatureInRAS</name>
      <label>Armature in RAS</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Whether input armature is already in the RAS(Right, Anterior, Superior) coordinate system (true) or in LPS (Left, Posterior, Superior) coordinate system (false, default). If not, it will be internally transformed into RAS.]]></description>
      <longflag>--armatureInRAS</longflag>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>

    <boolean>
      <name>BinaryWeight</name>
      <label>Use Binary Weight</label>
      <flag>-b</flag>
      <longflag>--binary</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[<b>For Debugging only.</b> Outputs binary weight instead of normal weights. Binary weights are simply the <b>Input Skinned Labelmap</b> region associated with each edge of the <b>Input Armature</b>.]]></description>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>

    <boolean>
      <name>RunSequential</name>
      <label>Run Sequential</label>
      <longflag>--sequential</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[Runs the computation of each bone sequentially instead of multi-threaded. By default, the module starts parallel threads to compute the weights. In this case the module consumes considerably more memory which may be an issue.]]></description>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>

    <integer>
      <name>MaximumParenthoodDistance</name>
      <label>Maximum Parenthood Distance</label>
      <longflag>--distance</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[Use this parameter to automatically prevent the propagation of the weight heat diffusion in region that belongs to bones too far in the family tree. For example, with <b>Maximum Parenthood Distance</b> set to 1, the diffusion will be limited to the bone's parent and children. The default (-1) means any distance is allowed, i.e. the weight can diffuse in any regions.]]></description>
      <default>-1</default>
    </integer>

  </parameters>

</executable>
