<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<executable>
  <category>;Segmentation.Bender</category>
  <index>6</index>
  <title>Pose Labelmap</title>
  <description><![CDATA[Pose an <b>Input Rest Labelmap</b> according to the input <b>Armature</b> pose and the associated weights.<p>The <b>Armature</b> and the weights should be associated with the volume the <b>Surface</b> originated from. For each surface voxel of the labelmap, the algorithm tri-linearly interpolates the input weight vector field. The resulting weight vector is used to blend the input armature transforms that is then applied to the voxel.</p><p>Since the computation can take time on fine volume, it is advised to first pose the skin and or skeleton model extracted from the <b>Input Rest Labelmap</b> to tweak the pose as necessary.</p>]]></description>
  <version>1.0.0</version>
  <documentation-url>http://public.kitware.com/Wiki/Bender/Documentation/1.0/Modules/PoseLabelmap</documentation-url>
  <license/>
  <contributor>Yuanxin Liu (Kitware), Julien Finet(Kitware)</contributor>
  <acknowledgements><![CDATA[This work is supported by Air Force Research Laboratory (AFRL)]]></acknowledgements>
  <parameters>
    <label>IO</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Input/output parameters]]></description>

    <image type="label">
      <name>RestLabelmap</name>
      <label>Input Rest Labelmap</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Original labelmap for which the <b>Armature</b> was created and the weights computed.]]></description>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>0</index>
    </image>

    <geometry>
      <name>ArmaturePoly</name>
      <label>Armature</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Armature in pose mode. The armature should be associated with the volume the <b>Input Rest Labelmap</b> it originated from.]]></description>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>1</index>
    </geometry>

    <directory>
      <name>WeightDirectory</name>
      <label>Directories containing all the weights</label>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>2</index>
      <description><![CDATA[Directory containing the weight image files (one for each <b>Armature</b> edge). These weights should be associated with the volume the <b>Input Rest Labelmap</b> they originated from.]]></description>
    </directory>

    <image type="label">
      <name>PosedLabelmap</name>
      <label>Output Posed Labelmap</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Output posed labelmap. It is the <b>Input Rest Labelmap</b> where each voxel was posed by the <b>Armature</b> pose transform.]]></description>
      <channel>output</channel>
      <index>3</index>
    </image>

  </parameters>

  <parameters>
    <label>Controls</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Control how the module operates]]></description>

    <boolean>
      <name>LinearBlend</name>
      <label>Use linear blend to pose</label>
      <longflag>--linear</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[If set to true, the pose transforms from the <b>Armature</b> will be combined linearly (according to the weights), which will result in rigid transforms. ]]></description>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>

    <integer>
      <name>MaximumRadius</name>
      <label>Maximum radius</label>
      <longflag>--radius</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[This property controls how far in the posed image the holes are filled. Should be a power of 2.]]></description>
      <default>64</default>
    </integer>

    <integer>
      <name>MaximumParenthoodDistance</name>
      <label>Maximum Parenthood Distance</label>
      <longflag>--distance</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[Use this parameter to prevent the interpolation of weights that are too far away in the family tree. For example, with Maximum Parenthood Distance set to 1, the interpolation will be limited to the bone's parent and children. The default (-1) means any distance is allowed.]]></description>
      <default>-1</default>
    </integer>

    <integer-vector>
      <name>HighPrecedenceLabels</name>
      <label>High Precedence Labels</label>
      <longflag>--high</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[List of label values (comma separated) that should take precedence when multiple labels are repositioned in the same output voxel. Highest precedence labels are listed first. For example, "209, 253, 111" would make the label 209 always overwrite the label 111 if they are repositioned in the same voxel. ]]></description>
    </integer-vector>

    <integer-vector>
      <name>LowPrecedenceLabels</name>
      <label>Low Precedence Labels</label>
      <longflag>--low</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[List of label values (comma separated) that should not take precedence when multiple labels are repositioned in the same output voxel. Lowest precedence labels are listed first. For example, "143, 5, 17" would make the label 17 always overwrite the label 143 if they are repositioned in the same voxel.]]></description>
    </integer-vector>

  </parameters>

  <parameters advanced="true">
    <label>Advanced</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Advanced properties]]></description>

    <boolean>
      <name>Debug</name>
      <label>Debug Mode</label>
      <longflag>--debug</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[Print debug logs and dump intermediate images.]]></description>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>

    <boolean>
      <name>IsArmatureInRAS</name>
      <label>Armature in RAS</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Whether input armature is already in the RAS(Right, Anterior, Superior) coordinate system (true) or in LPS (Left, Posterior, Superior) coordinate system (false, default). If not, it will be internally transformed into RAS.]]></description>
      <longflag>--armatureInRAS</longflag>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>

    <integer>
      <name>BackgroundValue</name>
      <label>BackgroundValue</label>
      <longflag>--background</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[Background scalar value]]></description>
      <default>0</default>
    </integer>

  </parameters>

</executable>
