<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<executable>
  <category>;Segmentation.Bender</category>
  <index>5</index>
  <title>Pose Surface</title>
  <description><![CDATA[Pose a <b>Surface</b> according to the input <b>Armature</b> pose and the associated weights. <p>The <b>Armature</b> and the weights should be associated with the volume the <b>Surface</b> originated from. For each surface vertex, the algorithm tri-linearly interpolates the input weight vector field. The resulting weight vector is used to blend the input armature transforms that is then applied to the vertex.]]></description>
  <version>1.1.0</version>
  <documentation-url>http://public.kitware.com/Wiki/Bender/Documentation/1.1/Modules/PoseSurface</documentation-url>
  <license/>
  <contributor>Yuanxin Liu (Kitware), Johan Andruejol (Kitware), Julien Finet (Kitware)</contributor>
  <acknowledgements><![CDATA[This work is supported by Air Force Research Laboratory (AFRL)]]></acknowledgements>
  <parameters>
    <label>IO</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Input/output parameters]]></description>

    <directory>
      <name>WeightDirectory</name>
      <label>Directory containing all the weights images</label>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>0</index>
      <description><![CDATA[Directory containing the weight image files (one for each <b>Armature</b> bone). These weights must be computed from <b>Armature</b> and the same volume <b>Surface</b> is extracted from.]]></description>
    </directory>

    <geometry>
      <name>ArmaturePoly</name>
      <label>Armature</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Armature model containing the bone poses. The armature must 'fit' inside <b>Surface</b>.]]></description>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>1</index>
    </geometry>

    <geometry>
      <name>SurfaceInput</name>
      <label>Surface</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Input surface to be posed. If the point data of the surface contains the weight informations, they will automatically be used to compute the new posed surface. If not, then the images in the weight directory will be used.]]></description>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>2</index>
    </geometry>

    <geometry fileExtensions=".vtk">
      <name>OutputSurface</name>
      <label>Output posed surface</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Output surface posed by the <b>Armature</b> transforms.]]></description>
      <channel>output</channel>
      <index>3</index>
    </geometry>

  </parameters>

  <parameters>
    <label>Controls</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Control how the module operates]]></description>
    <boolean>
      <name>LinearBlend</name>
      <label>Use linear blend to pose</label>
      <longflag>--linear</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[If set to true, the transform matrices of the <b>Armature</b> will be combined linearly (according to the weights), which will result in rigid transforms. ]]></description>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>

    <boolean>
      <name>ForceWeightFromImage</name>
      <label>Use weights from image</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Ignore the presence (or not) of the weight point data. Useful if the weight in the <b>Directories containing all the weights</b> have changed.]]></description>
      <longflag>--forceUseImage</longflag>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>
  </parameters>

  <parameters advanced="true">
    <label>Advanced</label>
    <description><![CDATA[Advanced properties]]></description>

    <boolean>
      <name>Debug</name>
      <label>Debug Mode</label>
      <longflag>--debug</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[Print debug logs and dump intermediate images.]]></description>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>

    <boolean>
      <name>IsArmatureInRAS</name>
      <label>Armature in RAS</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Whether input armature is already in the RAS(Right, Anterior, Superior) coordinate system (true) or in LPS (Left, Posterior, Superior) coordinate system (false, default). If not, it will be internally transformed into RAS.]]></description>
      <longflag>--armatureInRAS</longflag>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>

    <boolean>
      <name>IsSurfaceInRAS</name>
      <label>Surface in RAS</label>
      <description><![CDATA[Whether the input surface is already in the RAS(Right, Anterior, Superior) coordinate system (true) or in LPS (Left, Posterior, Superior) coordinate system (false, default). If not, it will be be internally transformed into RAS.]]></description>
      <longflag>--surfaceInRAS</longflag>
      <default>false</default>
    </boolean>

    <integer>
      <name>MaximumParenthoodDistance</name>
      <label>Maximum Parenthood Distance</label>
      <longflag>--distance</longflag>
      <description><![CDATA[Use this parameter to prevent the interpolation of weights that are too far away in the family tree. For example, with Maximum Parenthood Distance set to 1, the interpolation will be limited to the bone's parent and children. The default (-1) means any distance is allowed.]]></description>
      <default>-1</default>
    </integer>

  </parameters>

</executable>
